Guide to the Terman Engineering Center Building Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Terman Engineering Center building collection
1972-2001
SC0991
Harry Weese & Associates.
2.5 Linear feet
Collection pertains to the building designed by Harry Weese & Associates which housed the Terman Engineering Center from 1977 to 2010 and includes memos, correspondence, sketches, drawings, reports, specifications, and other materials. There are also a small number of undated photographs of the exterior and interior of the Center mounted to boards.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to the building designed by Harry Weese & Associates which housed the Terman Engineering Center from 1977 to 2010 and includes memos, correspondence, sketches, drawings, reports, specifications, and other materials. There are also a small number of undated photographs of the exterior and interior of the Center mounted to boards.
Access Terms
Harry Weese & Associates.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Buildings.;; Stanford University. School of Engineering.
Collection Contents
- Collection
  - Terman Construction, memos, sketches, reports, etc., 1972-76 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary outline specifications, April-May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Specifications for Terman Engineering Center, July 28, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Terman Engineering Center: paint samples (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Terman Engineering Center: sketches, plans, brochures for building dedication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Energy Economic Study, Terman Engineering Center, prepared by Taylor Systems Engineering, Inc., James M. Trowbridge, 16 January 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Terman Engineering Bldg. Assessment, Terman Beam Project, Prepared by Brian Carilli, June 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Terman Engineering Center, Interior Master Plan, July 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes and reports, assorted (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Frederick E. Terman Engineering Center [correspondence, miscellaneous materials] 1973-76 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rankin (Carroll S.) memos 1975-77 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Engr. Building – architects 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Engineering Building – program 1972-77 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Engr. Building – correspondence, etc. 1972-80 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New building – construction manager and architect selection (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Energy Conservation Project in Terman Bldg., 1980-84 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Memos, correspondence, drawings, 1974-81 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Drawings, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Design Development Report, Sept. 13, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Acoustical engineering issues (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Study of Natural Ventilation, May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cost model reports (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cost model breakdown (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Basement laboratory plan (architectural drawing) 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Presentation panels (photos on foam core boards) (Box 2, Folder 2)